<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="XMLFile.css"?>
<!DOCTYPE XMLFile SYSTEM "DTDTest.dtd">
<Events>
   
   
   <Event type="salon">
      <Title>Ask the Librarian</Title>
      

      <Info>We are very lucky to have member Irene Kistler, a school librarian and educator, 
      	visiting for our October Salon. She'll share how picture books are used in libraries and 
      	classrooms. Find out what teachers are looking for in books, what kids need, and how you 
      	can connect with librarians across our state. You won't want to miss this important conversation! 
      	Bring your notebook and plenty of questions. </Info>
      	<Location>Bonilla Science Hall Room 129<br />
      	University of the Incarnate Word<br />
      	4301 Broadway <br />
      	San Antonio, TX</Location>
      
      <Date>Oct 29, 2016 </Date>
      
      <Time>10:00 AM - 12:00 PM</Time>
   </Event>
   
<Event type="salon">
      <Title>Words and Pictures: A Perfect Marriage</Title>
      

      <Info>Picture books are a perfect marriage of images and text. 
      	But how do these collaborations work? How can writers support a visual narrative, 
      	without micromanaging? How might an illustrator expand the world of a manuscript? How might 
      	images and words play off each other, or create humor, or even opportunities for a child to think? 
      	Whether you're writing, illustrating, or doing both, this conversation is for you! Bring your 
      	notebook and, if you like, a published example of an interesting way images and text work together.</Info>
      	<Location type="line1">Barnes and Noble</Location>
		<Location type="line2">321 NW Loop 410</Location>
		<Location type="line3">San Antonio, TX</Location>
      
      <Date>Aug 27, 2016 </Date>
      
      <Time>10:00 AM - 12:00 PM</Time>
   </Event>
   
   <Event type="salon">
      <Title>Scary Picture Books</Title>
      

      <Info>Join us for a Halloween discussion of scary picture books and books about fear. 
      	What are the limits for picture books? How can illustrators and writers manage scary images and content? 
      	Bring a favorite related picture book and a notebook for writing/drawing exercises! </Info>
      	<Location type="line1">Barnes and Noble</Location> 
		<Location type="line2">321 NW Loop 410</Location>
		<Location type="line3">San Antonio, TX</Location>
      
      <Date>Oct 31, 2015 </Date>
      
      <Time>10:00 AM - 11:30 AM</Time>
   </Event>

   <Event type="class">
      <Title>Picture Books 101</Title>
      

      <Info>Always wanted to write a picture book? Dive into the world of this flexible, 
      	dynamic format. Discover how picture books differ from easy readers and how they are formatted. Picture books 
      	include many genres and can engage both children and adults. We’ll look at sample picture books 
      	and then turn to the work of attendees to apply topics we’ve discussed. This is the perfect workshop 
      	for those just starting or hoping to build a solid foundation for their creative work. </Info>
      	<Location type="line1">Bonilla Science Hall Room 129</Location>
      	<Location type="line1">University of the Incarnate Word</Location>
		<Location type="line2">4301 Broadway </Location>
		<Location type="line3">San Antonio, TX</Location>
      
      <Date>Jun 25, 2016 </Date>
      
      <Time>9:00 AM - 5:00 PM</Time>
   </Event>
   
<Event type="salon">
      <Title>Paths to Publication</Title>
      

      <Info>We invite those of you with and without publishing experience to join us in discussing the tricky 
      	questions we all face: 
Do I need an agent? A creative lawyer? How and where do I submit work? How do I know when my work is ready? 
How do I interpret rejections? Will this waiting EVER end? How do I transition into a new format, genre, or 
market? Do publishing trends matter? 
The Picture Book Salon is pleased to announce that two remote special guests will join the Picture Book Salon 
discussion on Paths to Publications, including Minju Chang, an agent from BookStop Literary Agency, and Aimee 
Bissonette, a picture book author (North Woods Girl and Miss Colfax’s Lighta) and lawyer who represents 
children’s writers. So bring your publishing questions for these industry professionals!!!! 
</Info>
      	<Location type="line1">Barnes and Noble</Location>
		<Location type="line2">321 NW Loop 410</Location>
		<Location type="line3">San Antonio, TX</Location>
      
      <Date>Oct 31, 2015 </Date>
      
      <Time>10:00 AM - 12:00 PM</Time>
   </Event>
   
<Event type="salon">
      <Title>Fun Facts! Creative Nonfiction Picture Books</Title>
      

      <Info>Whether you're a novice or veteran picture book creator, join our conversation 
      	about the current renaissance in creative nonfiction picture books! How do authors and 
      	illustrators distill complex topics into accessible, irresistible books? We’ll explore 
      	all manner of questions about the process and possibilities of nonfiction. You’re encouraged 
      	to bring your favorite published informational picture book (maybe your own!) and share what 
      	you think makes it sing and dance, or what you've learned from it. Whether your interest is 
      	biography, nature poetry, STEM subjects, history or more — come with questions, ideas, or 
      	just a notebook. We’ll do creative exercises, collect great titles and leave inspired to 
      	create great books! See you there!</Info>
      	<Location type="line1">Barnes and Noble</Location>
		<Location type="line2">321 NW Loop 410</Location>
		<Location type="line3">San Antonio, TX</Location>
      
      <Date>Jan 30, 2016 </Date>
      
      <Time>10:00 AM - 12:00 PM</Time>
   </Event>
   

   
<Event type="class">
      <Title>Revision: Finding a Story’s Heart</Title>
      

      <Info>No matter how much skill a writer brings to manuscript, every new project
begins as a mystery. Or, shall we be honest? A big mess. Agent Minju
Chang and her clients, Megan Maynor and Charlotte Sullivan Wild, draw
back the curtain to describe how they revise picture books — alone and
together — to find the heart of their stories. This session will provide strategies 
and guiding questions for navigating revision of fiction and informational picture books.
</Info>
      	<Location type="line1">The Loft Literary Center</Location>
		<Location type="line2">1011 S Washington Ave</Location>
		<Location type="line3">Minneapolis, MN</Location>
      
      <Date>May 07, 2016 </Date>
      
      <Time>1:00 PM - 2:10 PM</Time>
   </Event>
   

</Events>